<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Macdarwin's thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://macdarwin.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://macdarwin.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-27T11:10:12+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://macdarwin.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Guillaume Fradet]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress for Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://macdarwin.github.com/blog/2012/12/26/octopress-for-windows/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-26T21:15:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://macdarwin.github.com/blog/2012/12/26/octopress-for-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Installation of an Octopress Blog engine on Windows</h2>

<p>First, sorry for my english that will might be hard to understand sometimes&#8230;</p>

<p>This post is only a simplification of all the steps needed to have an Octopress blog engine working on Windows. This is not really hard but information&#8217;s aren&#8217;t gathered in one place.</p>

<p>As Octopress said: &#8220;You should be comfortable running shell commands and familiar with the basics of Git. If that sounds daunting, Octopress probably isn’t for you.&#8221;. Windows version follows the same rule&#8230;</p>

<h2>First of all the Prerequisites</h2>

<p>Octopress need 3 components: Git, Ruby and Ruby&#8217;s DevKit. These components need to be <strong>in the Windows&#8217;s PATH</strong> so please click on the good checkbox during setup.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Git: <a href="http://git-scm.com/">http://git-scm.com/</a></strong></li>
</ul>


<p>Widnows version of Git can be download easily from git&#8217;s official web site: <a href="http://git-scm.com/download/win">http://git-scm.com/download/win</a>.</p>

<p>Download and follow the instructions (be careful, don&#8217;t forget to add Git to the windows PATH). Normally this step is already done if you use Git and Github.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ruby : <a href="http://rubyinstaller.org/">http://rubyinstaller.org/</a></strong></li>
</ul>


<p>The best installer so far for Ruby on Windows, is made by RubyInstaller. You can download it here : <a href="http://rubyinstaller.org/downloads/">http://rubyinstaller.org/downloads/</a>.</p>

<p>Download and fellow the instructions. You have to add Ruby to the windows PATH. In the instructions that follow, the directory that you selected is identified as <code>&lt;RUBY_INSTALL_DIR&gt;</code>. Pay attention to the folder where you install Ruby, the path must not contain spaces.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ruby&#8217;s DevKit : <a href="http://rubyinstaller.org/">http://rubyinstaller.org/</a></strong></li>
</ul>


<p>Once again RubyInstaller made a good job for this too. You can download it here : <a href="http://rubyinstaller.org/downloads/">http://rubyinstaller.org/downloads/</a> on the left under &#8220;Development Kit&#8221;.</p>

<p>Download and unpack somewhere (ex: <code>C:\RubyDevKit</code>). In the instructions that follow, the directory that you selected is identified as <code>&lt;DEVKIT_INSTALL_DIR&gt;</code>. Again, pay attention to the folder where you install it, the path must not contain spaces.</p>

<p>Now you have to install the DevKit into your Ruby folder. To do that open a Command window and do the following:</p>

<pre>
cd <DEVKIT_INSTALL_DIR>
ruby dk.rb init
</pre>


<p>If you choose a <code>&lt;RUBY_INSTALL_DIR&gt;</code> that is not the default one, you have to edit the <code>/config.yml</code> file (generated in the <code>&lt;DEVKIT_INSTALL_DIR&gt;</code>) and change the Ruby&#8217;s folder path.</p>

<p>Continue with the following (in the same folder):</p>

<pre>
ruby dk.rb install
</pre>


<p>All the Prerequisites are installed now. We can go to the next step Octopress setup ;)</p>

<h2>Octopress setup</h2>

<p>Octopress setup is really easy, just clone the official Octopress repository : <a href="git://github.com/imathis/octopress.git">git://github.com/imathis/octopress.git</a> in a folder of your choice. In the instructions that follow, the directory that you selected is identified as <code>&lt;MY_BLOG_FOLDER&gt;</code>.</p>

<p>You can now do the following in a Command Window:</p>

<pre>
cd <MY_BLOG_FOLDER>
ruby --version # <- this should report Ruby version 1.9.3
gem install bundler
bundle install
rake install
</pre>


<p>Well you have now a version of Octopress that just need to be deployed.</p>

<h2>Next step and conclusion</h2>

<p>To be fully functional you need to choose you deploying method (Github, Heroku, RSync&#8230;). I will not explain those steps; octopress.org already explains that very well. Follow the instruction in <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/deploying/">http://octopress.org/docs/deploying/</a> and Enjoy !</p>

<p>I hope this post help in some point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
